<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://nuitka.net</id>
  <title>Nuitka Blog - Posts tagged stream</title>
  <updated>2023-01-31T18:39:51.414454+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://nuitka.net"/>
  <link href="https://nuitka.net/blog/tag/stream/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://ablog.readthedocs.io/" version="0.11.0rc2">ABlog</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nuitka.net/posts/first-nuitka-live-stream.html</id>
    <title>First Nuitka Live Stream</title>
    <updated>2022-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;section id="first-nuitka-live-stream"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, Saturday 15.01.2022, there will be not one, but two live
stream of me coding on Nuitka, and talking and chatting with visitors in
the Discord channel created specifically for this. I will go from 9-12
CEST and from 17-20 CEST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;a class="reference external" href="/pages/Streaming.html"&gt;dedicated page on the web site&lt;/a&gt;
which has the details. Spoiler, it’s free and I have no plans for
anything that involves a subscription of any kind. Of course, talking of
subscription, do also checkout the &lt;a class="reference external" href="/doc/commercial.html"&gt;Nuitka commercial&lt;/a&gt; offering. That is a subscription with adds that
protect your IP even more than regular Nuitka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to do this on a regular basis, and I will be happy to do this
even when nearly nobody shows up. It will be however your chance, and in
previous GSoC and generally, I made very good experiences with joint
sessions. So I hope you will help me pasting code snippets and Google
results in chat, and discuss the optimization that we are going to add.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come and join me there. &lt;a class="reference external" href="/pages/Streaming.html"&gt;Instructions&lt;/a&gt; here.
You know you want to do it. I know I want you to do to it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Yours,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Kay&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://nuitka.net/posts/first-nuitka-live-stream.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Tomorrow, Saturday 15.01.2022, there will be not one, but two live
stream of me coding on Nuitka, and talking and chatting with visitors in
the Discord channel created specifically for this. I will go from 9-12
CEST and from 17-20 CEST.</summary>
    <category term="Nuitka" label="Nuitka"/>
    <category term="Python" label="Python"/>
    <category term="compiler" label="compiler"/>
    <category term="stream" label="stream"/>
    <published>2022-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nuitka.net/posts/next-nuitka-live-stream-30-01-2022.html</id>
    <title>Next Nuitka Live Stream</title>
    <updated>2022-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;section id="next-nuitka-live-stream"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Sunday 30.01.2022, there will be the third live stream of me
coding on Nuitka, and talking and chatting with visitors in the Discord
channel created specifically for this. I will go from 9-12 CEST and from
18 CEST until probably at least 20 CEST, but it seems I tend to go
overtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="last-time"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Last time&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the last two streams are on my Youtube, these are around 4h videos,
done on the same day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second stream I was working on Onefile compression for all Python
versions, by making the location of another Python that for Scons we
sort of did already, reusable. So now, you can run Nuitka with Python2.6
and compile your legacy code, while with say 3.6 also installed on the
same system, you do the &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;zstandard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; compression. That will be used for
other things in the future as well. This is going to be part of the next
release and currently on develop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first stream, I also did a little bit of performance plans, but
mostly only showing people what I have there in stock, not actually went
there and I started work on a &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;upx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; plugin, such that DLLs for
standalone are compressed with that. That also required a bit of plugin
interface changes and research. This one works mostly, but will need
more live. Also I think I looked at reducing what is included with the
follow standard library option, getting very minimal distributions out
of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="this-time"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;This time&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All around, this last stream, was a huge success. I was a bit under the
weather last weekend, but we go on now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure yet, what to do. I might be debugging issues I have with 2.6
and a recent optimization, that prevents factory branch from becoming
the next pre-release, I might be looking at macOS still. And I might be
looking at the caching of bytecode demoted modules, that is kind of
ready to be used, but is not currently, which is a pity. And of course,
the Python PGO may get a closer look, such that e.g. it works for
standalone mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="how-to-join"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How to Join&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;a class="reference external" href="/pages/Streaming.html"&gt;dedicated page on the web site&lt;/a&gt;
which has the details. Spoiler, it’s free and I have no plans for
anything that involves a subscription of any kind. Of course, talking of
subscription, do also checkout the &lt;a class="reference external" href="/doc/commercial.html"&gt;Nuitka commercial&lt;/a&gt; offering. That is a subscription with adds that
protect your IP even more than regular Nuitka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="join-me"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Join me&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come and join me there. &lt;a class="reference external" href="/pages/Streaming.html"&gt;Instructions&lt;/a&gt; here.
You know you want to do it. I know I want you to do to it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Yours,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Kay&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://nuitka.net/posts/next-nuitka-live-stream-30-01-2022.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Today, Sunday 30.01.2022, there will be the third live stream of me
coding on Nuitka, and talking and chatting with visitors in the Discord
channel created specifically for this. I will go from 9-12 CEST and from
18 CEST until probably at least 20 CEST, but it seems I tend to go
overtime.</summary>
    <category term="Nuitka" label="Nuitka"/>
    <category term="Python" label="Python"/>
    <category term="compiler" label="compiler"/>
    <category term="stream" label="stream"/>
    <published>2022-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nuitka.net/posts/next-nuitka-live-stream-04-06-2022.html</id>
    <title>Next Nuitka Live Stream</title>
    <updated>2022-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;section id="next-nuitka-live-stream"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the coming weekend, Saturday 04.06.2022, there will be the next live
streams of me coding on Nuitka, and talking and chatting with visitors
in the Discord channel created specifically for this. I will go from
10-14 CEST and potentially also one in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="last-time"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Last time&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s actually been too long for me to remember what I did, but I do know
that it took some time to get it right. It probably was about caching,
but there are usually several topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do however think that I need to use my CI machine with more processing
power rather than my normal desktop, or maybe even both, because the
screen capture, compiling, VS Code, and all, may make the Video
otherwise stutter a bit too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="this-time"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;This time&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, streaming is a huge success or Nuitka, however time is also scarce,
and me starting new things, risks the release being bogged down by
stabilization phases that are extended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure yet, what to do. I think, I want to look at adding the &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
as a C type and/or specializing code for mix of &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;CLONG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; (C long value)
and &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;LONG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; (Python3 &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; object``) and &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;INT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; (Python2 &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
object). Right now adding &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; goes through a constant object, one that
is prepared, and not time consuming to reference, but still overhead to
use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="how-to-join-nuitka-live"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How to Join Nuitka Live&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;a class="reference external" href="/pages/Streaming.html"&gt;dedicated page on the web site&lt;/a&gt;
which has the details. Spoiler, it’s free and I have no plans for
anything that involves a subscription of any kind. Of course, talking of
subscription, do also checkout the &lt;a class="reference external" href="/doc/commercial.html"&gt;Nuitka commercial&lt;/a&gt; offering. That is a subscription with adds that
protect your IP even more than regular Nuitka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="join-me"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Join me&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come and join me there. &lt;a class="reference external" href="/pages/Streaming.html"&gt;Instructions&lt;/a&gt; here.
You know you want to do it. I know I want you to do to it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Yours,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Kay&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://nuitka.net/posts/next-nuitka-live-stream-04-06-2022.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the coming weekend, Saturday 04.06.2022, there will be the next live
streams of me coding on Nuitka, and talking and chatting with visitors
in the Discord channel created specifically for this. I will go from
10-14 CEST and potentially also one in the evening.</summary>
    <category term="Nuitka" label="Nuitka"/>
    <category term="Python" label="Python"/>
    <category term="compiler" label="compiler"/>
    <category term="stream" label="stream"/>
    <published>2022-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://nuitka.net/posts/all-in-with-nuitka.html</id>
    <title>All in with Nuitka</title>
    <updated>2022-12-09T08:22:42+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kay Hayen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;section id="all-in-with-nuitka"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After more than 10 years of working on the Python compiler Nuitka, and
at the age of 50, I have finally decided to take the plunge. My projects
“Nuitka” and “Nuitka commercial” are now my &lt;em&gt;day job&lt;/em&gt;, and I quit my
work in the Air Traffic Community, after working on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ARTAS"&gt;ARTAS&lt;/a&gt; (a software to create an Air
Situation Picture from radar and other sensors) for 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="why-now"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Why now?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is very good question. I feel I could have done this a long time
ago, and my heart was torn for a while, and also I prepared this for a
while now. Listing back to interviews from 4 years ago, it seems though
as if it had not been on the radar (pun intended).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So then I launched Nuitka commercial around 1.5 years ago, first as
vapor ware, with early bird customers, and meanwhile it has matured to a
point, where it is the obvious solution to many corporate users, with
big guys picking it up and small business as well. From startups, big
name technology giants, universities, mid sized companies, and from
individuals, I have all kinds of support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked my old job very much, but it was getting old, and I felt like
Nuitka needs me to fulfil my mission. And my wife needed my help with
driving her to work, which was getting the load to high, something had
to give. And it seems nothing related to what is called Nuitka (my wife,
and the compiler share the name) was going to be that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="what-will-change"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What will change?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already, ever since I launched Nuitka commercial, Nuitka has become way
more of a out of the box experience. It just works, and covers more
packages than ever before, and steps have been taken, to make it
possible to extend this even further with your help. Sure there are
still shortcoming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Nuitka has become very polished, and shows this very much that I
also love details and doing things correctly. I have conducted Nuitka
from day one as an attempt to create a software that would be usable to
the enterprise with a million lines of code, that they cannot check for
unsupported language features, so Nuitka is just fully compatible, to a
level of absurdity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having conducted Nuitka on a level of where a corporate business can
throw it’s code at Nuitka and have it just work, and reliably, this will
only improve now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally bugs have happened once in a while, but I was always more
careful. You know, like if this was for safety critical software, on
which lives might depend. Hard to not be affected by that stance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So lets talk about other ways I plan to expand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="nuitka-package-configuration"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Nuitka Package Configuration&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extending Nuitka with tweaks for package has become increasingly
simpler. Many previous plugins, e.g. for &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;torch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;tensorflow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, and
most recently &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;numpy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, and definitely also the Qt binding ones in the
future, have been or will be converted to Yaml configuration applied by
generic plugins that deal with DLLs, data-files, tweaks (called
&lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;anti-bloat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;) etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding stuff there is simple, and as of recently, there is even
documentation for it. This is going to be explained in a series of posts
detailing Nuitka package configuration, under the &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;package_config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must say it’s so much fun, I love working with it. But the goal is for
this to have you join it, and PRs are indeed starting to come in more
frequently it seems from first glance, but I need to make this more
known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="streaming"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Streaming&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have experimented with streaming in the past, and I absolutely love
it. Without my day job, effectively working two jobs at the same time, I
expect to have the time to do more of them in December and then on a
regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="python-3-11"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Python 3.11&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a separate post on this issue later this week. I am
scrambling to add support for it and it feels very far already. Many
basic tests already work, but more debugging will be needed. I hope
Nuitka 1.3 will add support for it, at least on the usual experimental
level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="how-you-can-help"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How you can help?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please become a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nuitka.net/doc/commercial.html"&gt;subscriber of Nuitka commercial&lt;/a&gt;, even if you do not
need the IP protection features it mostly has. All essential packaging
and performance features are free, and I have put incredible amounts of
works in this, and I need to now make a living off it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, I am far from being able to sustain my income from it, and I
am taking a risk with this effort, hoping for support from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nuitka commercial makes creating a Windows Service a blast. It has a
PySide2 that is compatible with Nuitka (I did make PySide6 compatible
myself, and backported it to PySide2), so if you need to stay on old
software. And for IP protection, it is just incredibly important to not
ship bytecode at all, and with Nuitka commercial, it protects your data
and files at runtime too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am bad at marketing, but good at software, which is one more reason to
purchase it. You know you love these kinds of people. Was that good
marketing? Also, there are share buttons on this page. Please try them
out and let people know about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In future postings, I will make it a regular thing to ask for help with
some of the technical tasks. Stay tuned, there might be something that
you can help with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="becoming-more-active"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Becoming more active&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the kind of person that would much rather do good stuff than to
talk about it, like when it finally supports Python 3.11, normal old me
would just mention it maybe on Twitter once, and have it in the
changelog only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to get away from that. I need to resume TWN (This week in Nuitka)
and have all plans to do it. Obviously I can get caught up in things,
and may just always do it later when there is more or better news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://nuitka.net/posts/all-in-with-nuitka.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>After more than 10 years of working on the Python compiler Nuitka, and
at the age of 50, I have finally decided to take the plunge. My projects
“Nuitka” and “Nuitka commercial” are now my day job, and I quit my
work in the Air Traffic Community, after working on ARTAS (a software to create an Air
Situation Picture from radar and other sensors) for 20 years.</summary>
    <category term="NTW" label="NTW"/>
    <category term="Nuitka" label="Nuitka"/>
    <category term="Python" label="Python"/>
    <category term="compiler" label="compiler"/>
    <category term="package_config" label="package_config"/>
    <category term="stream" label="stream"/>
    <published>2022-12-09T08:22:42+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
